Andrew Urquhart

Software Developer/ MBA/ MSA

(617) 309-6581 | Jamaica Plain, MA

andrewurg@gmail.com | http://www.andrewurguhart.com github.com/BostonTechie

Big Four accountant turned full-stack software engineer who loves finding creative solutions to address a company's needs. With 13+ years of accounting and auditing experience, I help bridge the communication gap between your business's financial needs and developing real-world solutions.

SKILLS

HTML | CSS | Javascript | Excel | NodeJS | React | React Native | ExpressJS | Jira | Confluence | Workday | MongoDB | PostgreSQL | Git | GitHub | Postman

EXPERIENCE

General Assembly, Remote | Software Engineer Fellow 9/2021 – Present

- Investment Rollforward Full-stack data entry web application, using Javascript, HTML, CSS, MongoDB, and RESTful routing deployed on Heroku
- Flashcards Web application, using Javascript, HTML, CSS allowing users to study HTML, CSS, and Javascript questions deployed on Github

WGBH Education Foundation, Boston, MA |

Affiliates and Consolidations Manager, May 2016 to May 2021 Senior Accountant, 2014 to May 2016

- Provide technical accounting and general management support to consolidated affiliates
- Review and approve journal entries prepared by staff
- Manage and develop staff on account reconciliations and use of accounting system
- Prepare and review consolidated balance sheet, statement of activities, cash flow, as well as detailed footnotes
- Review eliminations of affiliated entities, coordinate to resolve discrepancies
- Work with external financial statement auditors to gather support and resolve queries
- Review reconciliation monthly, including investments, cash, pre-payments, inventory, fixed assets, revenue, payables, and accounts receivable
- Leverage Excel programming expertise, to account for a \$300M endowment portfolio.
- Design, implement, and test re-design of accounting ERP system
- Design and review chart of accounts for newly acquired affiliate

Global Partners LP, Waltham, MA | Senior Accountant, 2013 to 2014

- Adjust general ledger via monthly reconciliation review and journal preparation
- Preparation of consolidation information monthly
- Primary backup to the treasury manager, including oversight of multimillion-dollar line of credit
- Prepared and reviewed quarterly disclosures for MD&A section of the financial statements
- Consolidated information of wholly owned affiliate into excel package

Ernst & Young, Boston, MA | Audit Senior, 2011 to 2013 Audit Staff, 2009 to 2011

- Responsible for execution of multi-year financial statement audits, Sarbanes-Oxley 404 internal control audits, and benefit plan audits
- Performed detailed audit testing of highly subjective and technical audit areas including inventory valuations, third party reserves, malpractice claims, environmental reserves, and deferred revenue
- Prepared and reviewed public filings of Form 10-K, Form 10-Q
- Developed relationships with clients by identifying and recommending process improvements to result in more efficient audits promoting growth
- Supervised new hires and second year staffs. Tasks included work assignment, ensuring account comprehension, and adoption of firm best practices
- Performed audit procedures over US GAAP financials and various areas of financial statement audit
 - Examples include cash, accounts receivable, accounts payable, inventory, accruals, revenue, expenses, third party reserves, environmental reserves, prepaid, fixed assets, debt, and equity
- Worked closely with managers, and partners on engagement teams to coordinate the completion of the audit in accordance with client deadlines
- Wrote performance reviews for staff on engagement teams. Discussed staff evaluations regarding reviews

EDUCATION

Software Engineering Immersive, General Assembly 9/2021 - Present

Six-month, 500-hour full-time, full-stack program. Gained hands on experience with the latest front-end and back-end programming languages, tools, and methodologies including HTML, CSS, Javascript, ReactJS, MongoDB, PostgreSQL, Express, NodeJS, Git, and Github

MBA / MSA, Northeastern University 8/2009

BS Economics, University of New Hampshire 5/2005